Which is the best health insurance plan in India? We will
discuss it in detail in today's
video. Today's video is going to be very important
because
I will also put before you some such terms and conditions of the companies, I will
cleanly expose them
which you might not be aware of till now. Many
times we feel later that the company did
not tell us, we had just signed the
policy randomly. We will discuss all such ifs and buts with
conditions, so this is a very
important video, please like it right now.
In health insurance in India,
mainly three companies are always talked about, the
first is the Optima
Super Secure plan of AGAC Argo, which is quite interesting, the
second is the
plan of n bp.in, we will discuss all these three plans
on many points and
put them before you. First of all, if we
talk about the clean settlement ratio,
here we
get the claim settlement ratio of 99.8 of ADAC Arco. I am
talking about this for the financial year 2020, at
that time due to the Covid pandemic, every one  It was becoming
very difficult for the company to settle claims because
a lot of
claims were coming in, so I personally
chose the most difficult plan here
hdfcergo.com
settlement ratio for us hdfcergo.com
is going to be expensive for you
hdfcfund.com point we never have to randomly choose a
cheap plan
because health insurance supports you and your
family at the time when
you are on bed and your family needs money, at that
time just because the
premium of any plan was low
and we get some if and but condition,
it can be a problem for us, but
I have told you that the most expensive
for you are
pre hospitalization expenses
hdfc0cpdccb suppose
even after you are hospitalized you are incurring some expenses,
some treatment is going on, for
how many days will your policy cover that, this is
its simple meaning, if we talk about room rent then
your policy will cover up to
₹ 2000000  If the cost
is above ₹5000000 then only single standard AC room
standard room will be covered for you,
deluxe or super deluxe room will not be covered for you
there is a room rent
limit for you which is a negative point
in Star,
how much will your road ambulance expenses be covered
ADAC is the best in this what ADAC says is
whatever your expenditure is, whether
you live in Delhi,
you have to go to Mumbai or
Bangalore, they will
cover it all in any ambulance, if you
talk about nv then they cover hospitalization at 22000,
if you talk about Star
then here the
limit of hospitalization and overall policy period is ₹7750, it
covers ₹1500000 and there is no sub limit in it but
in Star you will be charged a sub limit of ₹2000000
I am very sure now you have
understood why Star is cheaper,
you will understand in many points I am  I am simply putting forward the
points in front of you, in the
end you will have to study
and understand
which is actually the best plan for you, I will
also give my personal ranking towards the end of this
video and if
you have not yet taken a health insurance plan for your family,
then
check out the description and print comment,
you will get the number and details of our team
and our team will help you completely
wherever you will need to
take a plan. Health checkup: In health checkup,
if you first talk about HDFC, let's say a
cover of ₹5000000, your
sum shot is ₹1 lakh, multiply means 5 lakh, which means 5 lakhs have become 5
lakhs, multiply by 5, that is
₹2500000 for
every ₹5000000, you get ₹5000000, it is
important that in STAR also you will get the
option of prevent health checkup, if you
talk about copay, in ADAC and NV
you will not have any copay  It is not necessary to take the clause,
but if you talk about the policy, as soon as
your age is above 60 years, a copay of 20% becomes compulsory. The
waiting period is the same in all three policies,
but still I would like to tell you that
your initial waiting period is 30 days.
For such illnesses which are already listed, your waiting period is 2 years
and for pre-existing diseases,
your waiting period is 3 years. It is
absolutely same in all three policies. The
next and the most important point is the
restoration benefit. This is the most important answer, it is
very important for you to keep this in mind.
Suppose you have taken a policy of Rs 10 lakh
and in a particular year you get a
claim of Rs 5 lakh, then the balance sum
assured left with you is only Rs 5 lakh, but due to
this restoration benefit, your
initial total sum assured, i.e. Rs 10 lakh
in this case, will be restored back to you.  It will be restored,
and the entire sum assured will be
available to you, which is quite beneficial for you.
If you
talk about ADAC, then restoration is
applicable for the same person with the same disease. Suppose
someone in your family is hospitalized for
a major illness and you are incurring
repeated expenses on that illness,
then you will still get the restoration
benefit here, and
you can also avail the restoration benefit unlimited times.
You have to pay a small additional charge,
but according to me, in ADAC Optima Super
Secure, because you have this option
available for unlimited time restoration,
you should always take the unlimited time
restoration plan.
If we talk about your premium here, there is
only an increase of 1%, but there is a
lesser increase than 1%.
To avail this additional premium, it is important for you to take it.
Talking about Niva B or Max, here you
get unlimited restoration by default and I
feel this is the one of the
most important points of Niva B policy which is very good
and all other policies should give the
benefit of unlimited restoration to their clients,
this is my personal opinion, if
you talk about Star, then here
you get restoration once in a year,
same person, same disease is also excluded,
next bonus is also very important in all three plans and the
terms and conditions of bonus are very complicated for each policy,
I will try to present it for you in a very
simple way,
what does HDFC say here,
suppose you have taken a policy for one year, suppose your term is
10 lakh,
we will give you a bonus of 50% on that, that means
you will get an additional sum assured of 5 lakh
from the second year and as soon as you complete 2 years
of the policy, your sum assured will be increased.  ₹10
lakh means it will increase with a bonus of 100%.
This is the best point
hdfcfund.com This is an important point due to which
I like this policy very much.
If we talk about nv, then here
you get a bonus of 50% in the first year.
You get an additional bonus of 50%
in the second year, but only those years will be counted
where you do not have any claim. If
you made a claim in any year, then
you will not get a bonus there. Finally, if we
talk about Star plan, then
this bonus feature here is the most complicated and the
worst. According to me, what it says is that
you will get a bonus of 25% sum shot in the first year
and from the second year onwards, the
bonus of 10% sum shot will keep increasing. It
means it will take you more than 5 years
if you have to reach a bonus of 100%,
which I do not understand at all.
For example, if you ever made a
claim in any year, then the
amount of your bonus  It will be reduced from 10,
which becomes a negative point for us.
I
find the star bonus
rule the most complicated here and the simplest and best.
Companies also get the bonus whether there is a claim or not. The
client who has paid the money has the
right to it. He should get it. Next, there are two
points which are very important for you.
First of all, there is a point of
secure benefit. Secure benefit is available to you
only and only with
HDFC0000001 lakh, that is, it has become 20 lakhs.
10 lakhs is free from my side.
That is why this is a benefit which is
available only to HDFC and not in the other two policies.
What happens after this benefit?
Suppose you have taken a policy of 10 lakhs, then on the
first day your policy amount gets doubled. You get a
sum assured of 20 lakhs.
If you do not get any claim for 2 years, then
your policy
amount along with the bonus becomes 30 lakhs
and you definitely get restoration.  So
because of your restoration, the
total amount that you can claim can be
restored from 10 lakhs
and here you may think that if
for example I get unlimited restores in a Niva policy, a
policy of 10 lakhs, I will keep getting restores of 10 lakhs again and again, then what is the benefit of
secure benefit, it is
very beneficial, I will tell you
how, suppose you have taken an ADAC
policy of ₹10 lakhs and your
restore benefit has been activated on the very first day,
your claim comes for 15 lakhs,
your entire amount of 15 lakhs will be plus because
secure benefit is applied,
instead of this, if your single bill is the first, if you have
taken a Niva policy of 10 lakhs, your single
bill comes for ₹1 lakh, then
only 10 lakhs of yours will be cleared, the remaining 5 lakhs will
not be cleared because once your
10 lakh amount is cleared, only
after that it will be cleared  Restoration will happen; it does not happen first.
Therefore, Secure Benefit
is important for you because Secure Benefit
increases your base amount.
Bonus also increases your base amount,
but Restoration Benefit never increases your base
amount. This
is an important point. I hope you understand. Let's
move on to the next important point. Organ donor
facility
is not available at hdfcergo.com. Hospital network is more than 13,000
hospitals. ADFC has a
hospital network of more than 5,000 hospitals. Niva has a hospital
network of more than 11,000 hospitals.
Always insure wherever
you go for treatment. For example,
you live in a share or in Indore.
For example, are the
major hospitals in Indore covered in your policy?
Check beforehand so that
you do not face any problem later. You should get
cashless settlement later, which becomes
most important for you. Final
Important  Let's discuss two points.
First, we have
robotic surgery or modern treatment,
hdfc0000050 or ₹1 lakh, whichever is
lower. Therefore, you get capping on both these points.
But it is
not just hospital
expenditure. There are some additional
expenditures as well which come
in the exception list or exclusion list.
For example, gloves, masks,
nebulizers, foot, if we go to
hdfcfund.com, there is a list of exceptions
which your health insurance does
not cover. You can check this. This is one
such point where ADAC Arg has won by
default. We have to admit this. I
hope you have
understood all the important points of all three policies.
After discussing all these points, according to my
personal ranking,
ADAC Arg's plan comes first.
Second comes Niva Bappa i.e.
Max's plan. Third comes
Star's policy. If you want to ask me.
What is the most positive point of Niva Upa? Let me
tell you that.
If we talk about Niva Upa, then suppose
you took a Niva Upa policy at the age of 25,
your premium does not
increase until you make a claim. This is an additional clause there, which becomes
its most beneficial clause.
Similarly, if you ask me to
tell you some more points of ADAC, which is quite good,
there is that you
can apply a fixed deductible. What does fixed deductible
mean? Suppose you have
decided that whenever my
first claim comes in any year, I will pay a particular
amount of it, suppose Rs 50,000,
from my home. If you had applied this clause,
your premium would have been reduced by 40%. Check
out hdfcfund.com. If you
want to buy online yourself, at your own
convenience, you will still find important links
in the description.
Don't forget to check out. Happy learning and I will  see you very soon